Chen Hao.
陈浩
Feng Sir
冯科长
What are you doing here
这一大早的
so early?
跑这儿干吗来了
I'm coming for you.
我来找你的
This is the concession extradition treaty
您让我抄的
you asked me to manuscript.
租界引渡条约
Is that why
交这个东西
you come here so early?
用得着一大早过来
It's what I should do.
应该的
Your request is my top priority.
毕竟是交给您的
What were you doing yesterday?
昨天白天你在哪儿
I was training new officers at the Fourth House.
我在四所操练新的警员
Training?
操练
With such slow reaction?
就这反应还操练
Wang Yong.
王永
What're you doing?
干吗呢 这是
We exchange training experiences.
我跟陈队长操练操练
Are you okay?
没什么事儿吧
Yes, I'm ok.
没事儿
Thanks for your consideration
谢谢分局
for the Fourth House.
平日对四所的照顾
Next time you come,
下回来分局
make sure your shit is cleaned up.
收拾干净点儿
I got it.
知道了
If I may,
要是没什么事儿
Feng Sir,
冯科长
I'll go back now.
我先回四所了
Go ahead.
去吧
Thank you, Feng Sir.
谢谢冯科长
Nothing.
没事儿
[You know a lot, Wang Sir.]
还是王科长你有经验
[-Good morning -Wang Sir.]
王科长 早啊
[Good morning.]
早
[How about you?]
怎么样
[Everything goes well at home?]
家里都挺好的吧
[Fine.]
都挺好
[Tell me if you need any help.]
用不着我惦记
[I've done my meal.]
吃完了 回来了
[Good morning.]
早
[Make way!]
让一让 让一让
[Step aside!]
让一让
[Go about your business.]
忙你的事儿去吧
There is no need for you.
这儿不用你管了
Two months ago,
两个月前
there was a similar case,
发生过一起凶杀案
in which the victim had his throat cut, too.
死者也是被割喉
In every respect,
各方面情况
it is highly similar to the previous one
跟文华饭店的凶杀案
in Wenhua Hotel.
是高度相似的
The murderer of that case
那桩凶杀案的凶手
was executed.
已经被枪决了
Fourth House,
四所
get everything ready for handover.
准备一下资料移交分局
This is the man
这个人
you arrested from the
就是你们从法租界
French Concession?
带回来的
Take him.
带走
[The suspect jumped out of the car]
嫌疑人在移交途中
[during the transfer.]
跳车逃跑了
[Excuse me!]
让一下 让一下
[Good morning Zhao. Newspaper reading?:]
早啊 老赵 看报呢
[Yes.]
对 早啊
[Good morning.]
早
[Thank you, Sir and Madam.]
谢谢先生 谢谢太太
[Newspapers!]
卖报
[Fresh news!]
卖报啦
[Would you like a newspaper, Sir?]
先生 来份报纸吗
[Newspapers!]
卖报
Brother Yuansheng,
远生哥哥
are you sure you don't want to be a policeman?
你真不当警察了吗
Officers of the Fourth House
四所的人
make their living by
都是靠当警察
working as policemen.
养家糊口的
I don't want to
我不想把
drag them
这么一个小小的警察所
into trouble
卷进来
because of me.
把他们原本的生活打乱
If you leave,
你要是走了
Minmin would lose her partner.
珉敏姐姐就没有搭档了
She'll have a new partner sooner or later.
她迟早会有新的搭档
[Take a bite.]
吃一口
[Almost.]
差不多
[Or saw it]
还可以再稍微
[a little more.]
再多锯一点儿
[Just a little.]
一点儿
[I think it's fine.]
我感觉行了
[Okay.]
行
[Good morning, Yuansheng.]
早上好 向警官
[Look!]
你看
[We have eggs now.]
咱有鸡蛋吃了这回
[I'll tell you when]
一会儿红薯烤好
[the sweet potatoes are ready.]
我叫你啊
[Still a little long.]
这还是有点儿长
[Still?]
还长啊
[Yes.]
还有点儿长
[Give it to me.]
那拿过来
[I'll saw a little more.]
我再锯锯
[Just a little.]
锯点儿
[Dongbao,]
冬宝
[You only brought two chickens.]
你一共只带了两只鸡来
[Isn't the hencoop]
这么大个棚子
[too big for them?]
会不会修大了
[It's fine.]
没事儿
[I was thinking]
我都嫌这
[it may be too small.]
修得有点儿小呢
[The bigger the coop,]
你把它放到越大的地方
[the better taste the eggs have.]
它下的蛋越好吃
[Hongfa,]
鸿发
[give me a hand.]
来帮我扶一下
[I'll nail it.]
我再钉一下
[Be careful!]
你砸准点儿啊
[Don't worry.]
没事儿
[I'm an expert on this.]
我这干多少年了
[Dongbao,]
冬宝
[When can I]
这鸡什么时候
[eat the chicken meat?]
能给我吃啊
What? You want to eat them now?
不是 珉敏你现在吃它
I brought them out
我好不容易
with great difficulty!
从家里带过来的
I'm just joking!
我跟你开玩笑的
[Take it easy.]
我能真吃它们吗
[I will feed them]
回头我吃什么
[my food.]
给它们吃什么
[I'll look after them for you.]
我替你看着它们
[All right, you just don't eat them.]
行 你只要不吃它就行
[-Come over. -Hit with care]
来来来 砸利索
[Ok.]
行
[Do you prefer cabbage]
喜欢吃白菜
[or radish?]
还是萝卜呀
[Here!]
这儿有一个
[One more.]
再来一个
Captain,
队长
the potatoes are almost ready.
烤红薯马上好了
I'll get you one.
我给你拿过去
No, thanks.
不吃了
I got an upset stomach today.
我今天胃不太舒服
Has Xiang arrived?
向远生到了吗
He's inside.
在里面
Follow me.
你跟我进来
Close the door.
把门关上
Our chance has come.
机会来了
Read it.
自己看
The poster was Meng Duoci.
发启事的人是孟多慈
the daughter of the Meng couple.
孟氏夫妻的女儿
We speculated that the murderer
我们之前不是推测凶手
is after something.
应该是在找某个东西
It should be the key
应该就是这上面
mentioned here.
提到的钥匙
Tomorrow, the 26th,
二十六日 也就是明天
the murderer will go to the Jinmen Hotel.
凶手一定会去金门饭店
With concrete
我们只要提前
action plan,
把计划做好
we'll catch him this time.
这次一定能抓到他
Here is my resignation letter.
这是我的辞呈
Captain Chen.
陈队长
I come
我今天
to resign today.
是专门过来辞职的
Why?
为什么
I became a policeman by accident.
当警察算是个意外
I want to return to
我有我自己要做的事儿
my own life.
和另外的生活
I don't know what you did
我不清楚你来四所之前
before you came here.
是什么人
Whether you were from Party Affairs Department,
党务处的也好
or were a fishman,
打渔的也好
Or just travelled here,
旅游的也罢
I knew you came
但我知道你来四所
for this case.
就是为了查这个案子
But now you have the chance
现在机会来了
and you want to quit.
你却打退堂鼓
This case is no longer
这个案子现在
the concern of the Fourth House.
已经不归四所管了
It's not just me.
不光是我
You'd be better to stay out of it.
你最好也不要插手
You posted the notice, didn't you?
启事是你登的对不对
You want to investigate it
你想自己一个人
by yourself?
查这个案子
[I won't approve it!]
我告诉你 我不批准
I've made up my mind.
我已经决定了
Don't forget
你别忘了
you're still in your internship.
你还在实习期
If you quit,
你走了
Luo Minmin will lose her partner.
骆珉敏就没有了搭档
What will she do?
她怎么办
Find a new partner for her.
那就给她换个搭档
I don't have any extra officers
我没有多余的警员
for her.
安排给她
Can't she finish the test on her own?
一个人不能完成考核吗
It's the rule of the police station,
这是警察所的规定
not you or me.
不是你我定的
She's your partner.
她是你的搭档
You should be responsible
你难道不应该
for her!
为她负责吗
I've never
在这里
treated anyone as my partner.
我没把任何人当作搭档
[You guys...]
我说你们仨
Xiang Yuansheng wants to change a partner.
向远生说要换搭档
What're you doing?
干吗呢
Luo Minmin.
骆珉敏
Yes, Sir!
到
Why
委屈巴巴地瞪个眼睛
the long face?
给谁看呢
Do you feel wronged?
委屈吗
No, Sir!
不委屈
Remember,
记住
don't take it too seriously,
有些话别往心里去
understand?
明白吗
Yes, Sir.
我明白
Go about your business.
去忙你的
Yes, sir.
是
[Now.]
去
Think it through.
你想清楚了
If you decide to quit,
如果你决定不当警察
I'm not going to ask
接下来我不会对你
anything of you.
有任何要求
Once your internship is over,
实习期一到
you'll get a notice of dismissal.
你会收到辞退信
Tomorrow,
至于明天
whether you go or not,
不管你去不去
I will go there.
我一定会去
Today
还有
I went to
今天我去了一趟
Shiliupu Police Station.
十六铺分局
And I found out that
无意中看到
the case
这个案子的档案
is closed.
已经结案了
Closed?
结案了
Who's the murderer?
凶手是谁
A hobo.
无业游民
He owed money, killed and fled,
借款纠纷 杀人逃逸
then committed suicide after he was arrested.
被捕后畏罪自杀
They won't investigate
也就是说分局不会再
this case anymore.
查这个案子了
Do you really think
你觉得他们
they've found the murderer?
真的抓到凶手了吗
Captain,
陈队长
you asked me
你问我为什么
why I have been so stick
一直这么执着于
to this case.
这个案子
I want to ask you the same question.
同样的问题我也想问你
Why?
为什么
Because I'm a policeman.
因为我是一名警察
Why are you leaving so suddenly?
你为什么突然要走
The station house is just a small hole.
四所只是个小警察所
The policemen here
这里的警察
are also ordinary.
也都只是普通人
They don't have the capacity
根本没有能力
to investigate this case.
查孟家的案子
The Fourth House shouldn't get into this trouble,
四所不应该卷进来
and neither should you.
你也不应该卷进来
If we work
那万一
a little harder,
我们再努力一点
we might catch the murderer.
就抓到凶手了呢
What you should consider more is
你更应该考虑的是
the Fourth House are incapable
四所根本没有能力
of catching the killer.
抓到凶手
And it might even
甚至还有可能
get another penalty
因为这件事情
for this.
被第二次处罚
It's meaningless.
这么做毫无意义
Is it worth it?
值得吗
It may mean nothing to you.
可能你觉得不值得
But just as
这就像
doctors do not choose their patients,
医生不能选择病人
soldiers do not choose the battlefield.
军人不能选择战场
In my opinion,
我一直觉得
the same goes for the policemen.
警察也是一样
If you didn't like it,
你不喜欢四所
why did you become a policeman?
为什么还要来当警察
I'm not like you.
我和你不一样
I used up all my luck
我用光了所有的运气
to get to here.
才考到四所
And I like it more and more.
而且越来越喜欢这里
Maybe you think the house is
可能你觉得四所普通
ordinary or incapable.
或者能力不够
But I will never leave it
但是除非有一天它关门
unless
要不然
it is closed one day.
我是不会离开的
I respect your choice,
我尊重你的选择
but I have my own choice.
但我也有我的选择
If you really think
如果你真的觉得四所
the Fourth House can't achieve justice,
没有能力抓到凶手
you should stay.
那你就更应该留下来
It's not us who need you,
真正需要你的不是我们
but the
而是那些
victims who truly need justice.
真正需要帮忙的受害者
Dad,
爸爸
why are you here?
你们怎么来了
I've grown up.
我已经长这么大了
And I can go home
其实我是可以
by myself.
自己回家的
Officer Xiang.
向警官
Mr. Luo.
骆先生
Yuansheng, my father...
向警官 我爸想请你
Mr. Xiang,
向警官
I want to ask you something.
我想打听个事儿
Are you sure you Second House
你们这四区二所
won't be penalized?
确定肯定不受罚吗
Dad, it's the Fourth House!
爸爸 这里是二区四所
The Fourth House.
二区四所
It'll be fine.
四所确实没事儿了
My dad wants to invite you to dinner.
我爸爸想请你吃个饭
Later,
你一会儿
come to my house
带着你的妹妹呢
with your sister.
来家里一趟
I have something to tell you.
我有事儿要跟你说
And
那个 向警官
my father bought a fish
我爸爸特地去菜场
in the market
买了条鱼
to cook you braised fish.
要给你做红烧鱼吃
Remember to bring Qiushi with you.
你记得带上秋实一起来
[Luo Qinqin,]
骆勤芹
[How can you]
你怎么单独
[talk to a boy alone!]
跟男生聊天呢
[Tell her to bring her homework.]
让她带上她的功课
[I promised to tutor her.]
我答应要帮她辅导的
[I'll tell dad later.]
我一会儿就告诉爸爸
[We're all waiting for you at home!]
我们都在家等你啊
[Waiting for you!]
一定要来
[You bad girl.]
不学好
Someone wants to invite you to dinner,
有人要请你吃红烧鱼啊
Officer Xiang?
向警官
How did you find here?
你怎么找到这儿来了
It's easy for me to know
我想打听个警察所
a station house.
还不容易吗
Do they know who you are?
他们知道你是谁吗
Son of the Undersecretary of Ministry of Military Affairs
军政部次长的儿子
works as a recruit in such a
跑到这么个警察所里
small station.
当新兵
You can't even use your real name.
连真名都不敢用
And now you're going to a policewoman's house
现在还要去女警员家里
for braised fish.
吃红烧鱼
Are you in love
你小子谈恋爱了
with that girl?
跟那个女警员啊
What're you talking about.
开什么玩笑呢
Well, if it's not,
那既然不是
then tell me
就说说吧
what you are on.
你到底在玩什么游戏啊
Give me half a month,
给我半个月的时间
after that,
半个月后
I'll tell you everything.
我一定给你交代
I heard that
我知道
some time ago,
前段时间
a man from Navy Department
海军部有人
was arrested on your father's
在你父亲的生日宴上
birthday party
被捕了
for collaborating with the Communist Party.
因为通共
Just tell me the truth.
你跟我说句实话
What you're doing now
你现在做这些
has anything to do with Deng?
跟那个姓邓的有关吗
Why do you ask?
干吗突然问这个
Someone has asked me
有人已经向我打听
about it.
这件事情了
Tell me the truth.
我再问你一次
Do you have anything to do with him?
到底有没有关系
It's my choice to become a policeman.
当警察是我自己的事情
It has nothing to do with anyone else.
跟其他人都没有关系
Fine.
行
I'll take it as if
那我就当你是
you've been in military school
在军校待久了
for a long time,
现在神仙下凡
and now come out to experience life.
看什么都新鲜好玩
But be careful
但是玩归玩
not to get yourself into trouble.
别引火上身啊
I've gotta go.
我走了
Don't forget you owe me an explanation.
记得你欠我个交代啊
Go to
赶紧去吃
eat your braised fish.
你的红烧鱼去吧
[Steamed meat buns!]
小笼蒸包
[Fried fish!]
煎鱼
Make way for me.
来 快腾腾地儿
I'm coming.
来 来 来
It's my favorite
又是我最喜欢吃的
braised fish!
红烧鱼
You like the braised fish?
你喜欢吃这鱼啊
Then bring your brother here more often.
那以后多带你哥哥来
Okay!
好
Uncle Luo,
骆伯伯
Can I eat it now?
我现在可以吃鱼吗
Of course!
当然了
Let's eat.
当然 当然
Thank you uncle Luo.
谢谢骆伯伯
[Brother,]
哥
[I don't expect anyone]
没想到还有人
[to like your cooking.]
喜欢吃你做的菜
[You should have more faith on me]
好
[Thanks.]
谢谢
[Are you OK with eating spicy food?]
怕不怕辣啊
[I'm OK.]
还行
[Have a taste.]
你尝尝
[Do you like it?]
怎么样
[Yes, I do.]
好吃
[Is it delicious?]
好吃吗
[Eat more if you like it.]
好吃就多吃
[OK.]
好
Looks like
看样子
I can't object to my daughter
我女儿当警察的事儿
being a policewoman.
我是反对不了了
I invited you to dinner today
我今天找你来吃饭呢
to ask you a favor.
我就是有事相托
She's that kind of girl.
这个丫头上学的时候
Even if you gave her the exam answers,
你就是给她答案
she would get them wrong.
她都会写错的人
Speaking of her,
她呀
her brain is average.
脑子普通
And she looks average.
模样也普通
When she walks in the street,
要把她放到大街上
no one will notice her.
别人都不会多看她一眼
But now she's become a police officer.
你说她跑去当警察
I don't expect her to get credit.
我不求她有功
I just want her to come home safely every day.
每天平平安安回来就好
I'm telling you this today
我今天跟你说这些呢
to ask you a favor.
我就是想拜托你
Since you are partners,
既然你们是搭档
please take care of her.
今后多照顾着她点儿
Mr. Luo,
骆先生
I am sorry.
抱歉
I can't help you with that.
这件事情我答应不了
I'm not a policeman anymore.
我现在不是警察了
You quit?
你不当警察了
Yes.
对
Are you saying
那你的意思是
that my daughter has no partner
我女儿在四所
at the Fourth Station House?
没有搭档了
This is a test I prepared for my students
这个是我做家教的时候
when I was a tutor.
给学生准备的题
After you finish it,
你做一遍
I'll know exactly
我就知道
where to start tutoring you.
从哪儿开始辅导你
Treat it
我们要像
like a real test in school.
在学校考试一样
You need to write your name.
你要写上名字
I'll score you. OK?
最后我来打分好吗
OK.
好
Let's begin.
开始吧
Li.
李师傅
[Coming.]
来了
Tianxiang, may I help you?
天祥 有事儿啊
Do you have time?
您有时间吗
I want you
我一会儿想请您
to send two of my friends home.
送我两个朋友回家
Who can refuse when business comes knocking?
有生意谁不做呀
Allow me to wear my straw cape.
那我进屋穿个蓑衣
Wait a second.
你稍等我一会儿
Thank you.
麻烦您了啊
No worries.
不麻烦 不麻烦
[Careful.]
慢点
[I'll help you with the umbrella.]
我帮你打着伞
Learn hard from your brother.
回去好好跟哥哥学习
My dad always
我爸爸爱说一些
talks nonsense.
不着边际的话
Don't pay any attention to him.
你别往心里去
Officer Luo,
骆警官
it was an accident that I joined the force.
其实我来四所是个意外
It was also an accident that
甚至我来上海
I came to Shanghai.
都是个意外
Someone asked me to deliver something
有人托我给上海的朋友
to his friend in Shanghai.
送一份礼物
I was supposed to leave
我本应该在
after the gift was delivered.
礼物送到之后就离开
I have my own thing to do.
我有自己要做的事儿
It's not in Shanghai.
它不在上海
And it's not in this station house.
更不在这间警察所
I never thought
所以我从来没有想过
I would be expected of anything
自己会以警察的身份
as a policeman.
被人期望什么
So,
所以
you're saying that we're not partners.
你说我们不是搭档
For me,
对我而言
a partner is someone
搭档是能够沿着一条路
who goes the same way as mine.
一起走下去的人
I knew
我知道自己
I would leave the station house someday.
迟早会离开四所
If we don't walk
如果我们都不在
on the same way,
同一条路上
how can we be partners?
又怎么能成为搭档呢
Captain Chen is right.
陈队长说得对
You're doing great at the station house.
你在四所做得很不错
You can be a good policewoman.
你能成为一个好的警察
You have a better chance
至少比我
than I do.
更有可能
Sister,
姐
I read the homework
我看了向警官
Yuansheng gave Qiushi.
给秋实布置的作业
I can tell
他一看就是
that he studied well.
认真读过书的人
Maybe
说不定啊
he went to college before.
还上过大学呢
He was ten points below me
他入职考试
in the entrance examination.
比我还低十分呢
You know nothing
你还真是对这个人
about him.
一无所知啊
Did you see his watch?
你看他戴那手表没
He's smart, rich,
人家不仅聪明 家世好
and he looks like Clark·Gable.
长得还像克拉克·盖博
He's not from the same world
他跟四所警察
as the policemen
根本就不是
in the Fourth Station House.
一个世界的人
Yuansheng's sister
连向警官的妹妹
is awesome, too.
都这么厉害
Are you talking about Qiushi?
你说秋实
Check this out.
你看
She got all the questions
我给她布置的题
I gave her right.
她全都做对了
She didn't get a single question wrong.
一题都没做错
Unbelievable.
这家伙
She will definitely
这以后是要
go to college someday.
上大学的人啊
Look at the name.
这名字
Why did she alter it?
这名字怎么涂涂改改的
She must have written it wrong.
写错了吧
Even I couldn't write my name wrong.
我名字都不会写错
What's the fussy about?
干什么呢 一惊一乍的
Meng Duo...
孟 多
What's wrong?
怎么了 什么孟多啊
[Mr. and Mrs. Meng, famous businessmen]
沪上名商
[in Shanghai, were killed.]
孟氏夫妇遇害身亡
[They had a daughter.]
死者二人育有一女
[She is Meng Duoci, eight years old.]
名孟多慈 八岁
[She is suspected of missing or killed.]
疑失踪或同遇害
[Doesn't your mom braid your hair]
那你在家的时候
[when you are at home?]
妈妈不帮你编辫子啊
[My parents are not]
我爸爸妈妈
in Shanghai.
他们不在上海
Then she won't
那她岂不是很长时间
see her parents
都见不到
for a long time.
自己的爸爸妈妈了
Yes.
对
[Sister,]
姐
[Qiushi said that]
秋实说
[Yuansheng had been taking care of her.]
一直是向警官在照顾她
[She couldn't go to school]
好像有什么原因
[for some reason.]
不方便上学
[Yuansheng has been]
反正功课都是
[teaching her.]
向警官在教
She said her parents were not in Shanghai.
她还说她父母不在上海
Yeah.
是啊
No one knows
那俩人也不知道
where they are.
去哪儿了
If there was such an older brother
不过要是有
taking good care of me,
这样的哥哥照顾我
I would be happy, too.
换我 我也愿意
Don't you think it's strange for him
你不觉得向警官
to go to your station house
去你们警所当警察
as a police officer?
很奇怪吗
He's smart and rich,
他人聪明 家世好
and he looks like a movie star.
长得还像电影明星
What you should be thinking about is that
你更应该考虑的是
the Fourth Station House doesn't have
四所根本没有能力
the ability to catch the murderer.
抓到凶手
It might receive
甚至还有可能
another penalty
因为这件事情
for this.
被第二次处罚
There is no point in doing so.
这么做毫无意义
Is it worth doing?
值得吗
He's keeping Qiushi with him.
他把秋实一直带在身边
He came to the Fourth Station House
来四所就是
to look into this case.
为了查这个案子
He dares to do
他连别人最害怕的事情
even what others fear the most.
都敢做
How could he say that it was not worth it?
他怎么会觉得不值得呢
[Sister,]
我说姐
[What are you talking about?]
你在说什么呀
[Are you listening to me?]
你有没有在听我说话呀
[Dad.]
爸
[Why is there]
这厨房里
[a cake in the kitchen?]
怎么还有一个蛋糕啊
Silly me,
你看我这个脑子
I bought it
我那是给
for Qiushi.
秋实小丫头买的
I was busy and forgot the cake.
你看这一忙吧就忘了
It's fine.
那没事儿
Ask Minmin to take it to the station house.
明天让珉敏拿四所去
Then ask Yuansheng
然后让向警官
to take it home
给她拿回去
for her.
不就完了
He's left the Fourth Station House.
那人已经不在四所了
I don't think
你妹呀
your sister knows his address.
也不一定知道他的地址
Did Li
刚才是不是
give them the ride?
李师傅送他回去的
Yes.
对
How about this?
你这样呢
Ask him about his address.
你问问地址
Since I've bought it,
你看我买都买了吧
you'd be better to send it to her.
还是给她送过去吧
OK, I'll go now.
行 那我现在去一趟
OK.
好
Li,
李师傅
are you just off work?
您才收车啊
Tianxiang.
天祥
Do you remember
您还记得
the two people
我下午让您送的
I asked you to give ride?
我那两个朋友
What's their address?
您给送到哪儿了
I sent them to Wangyun Road.
我送到望云路了
What's the number?
望云路几号呀
No. 23, Wangyun Road.
望云路二十三号
OK, I see.
行 我知道了
I'll leave you alone.
您赶紧忙吧
See you.
我回家了
How about we eat together at your place?
我们也去你家吃啊
Last time we asked you for money.
上次找你要钱
You said half a month.
你说半个月给我
Where's the money?
钱呢
I'm asking you where's the money?
问你话呢 钱呢
I can't get that
我 我实在凑不出来
much money.
那么多钱
You know
你们也知道
I work in a mahjong parlor.
我在麻将馆打工
My salary is small.
薪水就那么点儿
Shame on you.
看你这怂样
I thought you were
我记得之前
a zinger.
挺精神一人啊
How could you become a coward
怎么抓了个壮丁
after being
充了个军
conscripted into the army?
怂头怂脑的
Tianxiang,
天祥
Listen up.
我跟你说
We will come to get the money
明天下午
tomorrow afternoon.
我们准时过来拿钱
If we can't get the money,
拿不到钱
not only will I
我不但把你当逃兵的事
report you as a deserter,
告发出去
but I will also
还一把火
burn down your shop.
把你家铺子给烧了
Believe it or not.
你信不信
Please don't.
你 别别别
My dad is an honest man.
我爸是老实人
The photo shop has been his entire life.
这照相馆是他的心血
About the money,
钱
I'll try to get it
我 我明天想办法
for you tomorrow.
给你们凑
Keep your word.
说话算话
See you tomorrow.
明天见
Let's go.
走
[Someone is]
有人哪
[looking for the girl]
要找这照片上的
[in the photo.]
小女孩儿
The reward is a hundred silver dollar.
开价一百块
[How much?]
多少
[A hundred silver dollar.]
一百块
Secretary Guo and the Chief
郭秘书长跟参谋长
will be out in a minute.
马上就出来了
The car is ready.
车已经备好
It's raining heavily.
下这么大雨
Why don't you use an umbrella?
魏队长也不说打把伞
Secretary Guo came from Nanjing
郭秘书长这次从南京
to visit us.
特意赶过来
You have to
这顿饭
escort the chief
参谋长只得
to dinner
劳烦魏队长你
in person.
亲自护航了
Consider it done.
这是我应该做的
Chief Tong,
佟参谋长
you must be joking.
是真会开玩笑啊
How's your father?
令尊身体还好
Thank you for asking.
劳您惦记
He's in good shape as always.
还是那一如既往地好
He asked me how you were the other day.
前两天还跟我打听
And wanted to play mahjong with you.
要跟你打牌呢
I've been busy with business lately.
最近确实是公务繁忙
I'll pay him a visit later.
改天一定登门拜访
Please tell his respectful
请转告老爷子
I won't go easy on him
再打牌
next time.
我可不让着他了
Sure,
一定
I'll tell him.
一定带到
Take care.
慢走
Please.
请
You must be Captain Wei.
这位就是魏队长吧
Yes, Sir!
报告
I am Wei Daiqing.
卑职魏岱擎
I'm the head of the investigation team
现任淞沪警备司令部
of Shanghai Garrison Command.
侦查队队长
Over.
报告完毕
I heard
前段时间
it was you who went to Nanjing
海军部的共谍案
and arrested
听说就是你
CPC espionage in the Navy Dept.
去南京抓的人
Yes, it was me.
是 是卑职干的
I caught the spy
当时卑职是在
in the house of Undersecretary Hua
南京军政部
of the Ministry of Military Affairs.
华次长家里抓的人
The prisoner is still on trial.
目前人犯还在审讯之中
Chief Tong,
佟参谋长
many people complain about
眼下有很多人抱怨
the party's lack of vitality.
党内暮气沉沉
I don't think so.
我看未必
Here's a pillar
这不就是
who's bold
我们既有魄力
and vigorous.
又有锐气的中流砥柱吗
Uncle,
三姨父
Secretary Guo came all the way from
郭秘书长这次
Nanjing military prosecution
突然从南京监察院
to Shanghai.
来上海
I don't think
不光是来
he's just here for
警备司令部办事
the Garrison Command.
这么简单吧
You are right.
你也看出来了
Did he come for the case
他是冲着魏岱擎
Wei Daiqing is up to?
查的共谍案来的
If it weren't for the case,
如果不是因为这个案子
how could he, the Secretary,
堂堂的监察院秘书长
talk to a small potato
怎么会跟魏岱擎
Wei Daiqing?
这种小角色搭话呢
What's the mystery
您说邓铭远的案子
of Deng Mingyuan's case?
到底有什么奥妙啊
Why did the military prosecution come?
能把监察院也吸引过来
It's like two tigers fighting.
说到底不过是虎狼之争
Since Kong took over the Treasury,
财政部自从改姓孔之后
he was criticized a lot
这两年党内
from inside of the party.
对其抨击之声不断
The Elder,
元老派
the Political Science,
政学系和
and the CC cliques (Central Club)
CC系（中央俱乐部）
are waiting for their chance to bring Kong down.
一直在伺机倒孔
[Secretary Guo]
郭秘书长以前是
[was the backbone]
CC系（中央俱乐部）的
[of the CC clique.]
骨干
[While undersecretary Hua]
而华次长
[is Kong's man.]
恰恰吃的是孔家饭
[This time,]
这次
[Wei Daiqing caught a communist]
魏岱擎在华次长家里
[at Undersecretary Hua's home.]
抓到了一名共产党
[Tell me,]
你说
[how about it?]
抓得妙不妙
I heard you applied
我听说
to the Party Investigation Division
你向南京党务调查处
for access
申请查看
to Undersecretary Hua's review record.
华次长的审查记录
I did.
是
But I was rejected.
但是卑职被拒绝了
Nanjing has placed great emphasis on
邓铭远的案子
Deng Mingyuan's case.
南京方面一直很关心
Because he had served in the Navy Dept
毕竟他在海军部
for a long time.
待了很久啊
And this case involved
况且这个案子还涉及到
Undersecretary Hua.
军政部的次长
It's normal
有点儿阻力嘛
to meet with resistance.
也很正常
It is my duty to serve the party-state.
为党国效忠 责无旁贷
No matter how much resistance there is,
无论有多大的阻力
I'll get to the bottom of that.
卑职要一查到底
I believe
而且我相信
a senior
像华次长那样的
like Undersecretary Hua
党内老人
can stand up to investigation.
也不会经不起调查
Before I came to Shanghai,
来上海之前
I talked to a friend about Deng Mingyuan.
我和朋友聊过邓铭远
Before boarding Ship Yong Feng
在他登上永丰舰
and becoming a second mate of former president,
成为先总理的二副之前
he was an ordinary navy.
他就是一名普通的海军
Some people
有些生命啊
live in the darkness.
他本来身处暗夜
It takes only one
也许只需要一次
encounter with superior power
与权力的遭遇
for him to embrace brightness.
就可以跳出暗夜
Otherwise,
否则他们匆匆逝去的
there would be nothing left
短暂一生
in their fleeting lives.
不可能留下只言片语
Deng Mingyuan is no exception.
对邓铭远如此
So are
对其他人
others.
也是如此
Captain, we got a hit.
队长 有线索了
[Looking for a gentleman from the South.]
寻南方先生
[Meng Duoci.]
孟多慈
The person Meng Duoci was looking for
孟多慈找的这个人
was likely to be a communist close to
很有可能跟邓铭远一样
the Mengs, just like Deng Mingyuan.
是孟家亲近的共产党
If someone comes
待会儿要是真有人
to pick up the keys,
来取钥匙
don't rush.
你们别忙着动手
Follow him
跟着他
and see where he goes.
弄清楚去处
Got it.
明白